Emergency! Wake up!
緊急情況！醒醒！
-It's an emergency! Wake up! -Ax!
-緊急情況！醒醒！ -斧頭！
-Is it an ambush? -Madame Ryu's summons.
-有埋伏嗎？ -柳閣長召喚我們
I don't know why, but she's gone wild.
不知道有什麼事，但她已經發瘋了
EPISODE 8
（第 8 集）
What? Why?
幹嘛？怎麼了？
The cabbage from the seas are firm and hearty.
海風吹過的白菜結實又飽滿
-Taste all good with the shrimps? -It's refreshing, without a fishy smell.
-放蝦好吃嗎？ -很爽口，一點腥味都沒有
-Please save me, boss. -What are you doing there?
-老大，救救我吧 -你在這裡做什麼？
I thought there was an emergency?
不是有緊急情況嗎？
One of Myoyeongak's biggest events is obviously an emergency.
妙緣閣最隆重的活動當然是緊急情況
-Sit down, the three of you. -It's gimjang season?
-你們三個都坐下 -到醃泡菜的季節了？
-I'm a former mountain god. -I'm the boss of a bandit gang.
-我是前任山神 -我是土匪幫頭目
I'm a victim of the bandit gang.
我是土匪幫的受害者
-A former god never makes kimchi. Geez. -Hold on.
-前任山神從來不做泡菜的，真是的 -等等
I've calculated your lodging expenses. You've been indulging free of charge.
我有計算你們的住宿費 你們一直在白吃白喝
It sums up to at least the cost of a house!
這些費用加起來至少能買一棟房子了
-How is it so expen-- -I told you not to eat full course meals!
-怎麼這麼貴… -我就叫你不要吃得那麼豐盛！
You ate most of it!
大部分都被你吃了！
Oh, well…
那個…
Don't I get a discount? We're friends and I'm a former god, no?
不能給我打折嗎？ 我們是朋友，而且我是前任山神
Not a chance, you punk.
做夢，臭小子
Geez, it's not like I've ever done this before.
天哪，我從來沒做過這個
Seriously.
真是的
Gosh, my back.
哎呦，我的腰
Do we really need to make 500 cabbage heads worth of kimchi?
我們真的要做出 五百棵白菜那麼多的泡菜嗎？
I'm a bandit, but I have red pepper instead of blood on my hands.
我明明是土匪 手上沾的卻不是血，而是紅辣椒
-Well, I'll say! -Kimchi tastes best homemade.
-就是說嘛！ -自製的泡菜最好吃
Make sure to fill it up.
一定要裝滿
-Hey, but isn't this a bit too salty? -Really? Let me try.
-喂，這也太鹹了吧？ -真的嗎？給我嚐嚐
It's just right. It should be salty to ferment it in a crock.
剛剛好，就是要鹹一點 才能放在缸裡發酵
-Is that so? -Be meticulous.
-是嗎？ -細心一點
-It should be salty. -It's delicious!
-鹹就對了 -好吃！
Hey, you two!
你們兩個！
Gosh, seriously.
真是的
Sir, I can't share rooms with him. We're so incompatible.
大人，我不能和他睡一個房間 我們兩個水火不容
Gosh, you're gonna rat me out?
天哪，你竟敢告我的狀？
So why did you rob him of all people? He can be really vindictive, you know.
你幹嘛非要搶劫他？ 他這個人特別記仇
How could he have known? Just commend him for his professionalism.
他怎麼會知道？ 這種專業精神可圈可點
Exactly. Who's the idiot taking drinks without knowing what's in it?
對嘛，想都不想 就喝人家酒的笨蛋是誰啊？
You thief.
你這個小偷
Hey, blaming the victim is still uncalled for!
喂，沒必要責怪受害者！
-Don't yell at my henchman! -Don't talk back to your brother!
-不要吼我的副頭目！ -不要和哥哥頂嘴！
Don't tell my boss what to do!
不要命令我們老大！
-Shut up and kimjang! -Get your hands--
-閉嘴，醃泡菜！ -把你的手…
Even Gyeongseong's changed quite a bit.
連京城都變了
Speak in Korean, you idiot.
講韓語，笨蛋
K-- Korean. H-- Hard.
韓…韓語，好難
It's been twenty years since you've learned Korean.
你學韓語已經二十年了
You guys the Shinigami Mercenaries?
你們是死神僱傭兵團嗎？
-I'm on orders to pick you up. -You work for Kato, but you don't know us?
-我奉命來接你們 -你是加藤的手下，卻不認識我們？
This is Gyeongseong. I don't care about you hillbillies.
這裡是京城 我才不在意你們這些鄉巴佬
Shall we tell you who we are?
要我們亮出身份嗎？
There are many eyes watching.
很多雙眼睛看著呢
-Are you waiting for Lee Rang? -No, ma'am.
-妳在等李朗嗎？ -沒有
If not, what's all this?
如果沒有，那這是什麼？
Magazines say folding paper cranes will make your love come true.
雜誌上說，折千紙鶴 能讓你得到你愛的人
Goodness. You like him that much?
天哪，妳就那麼喜歡他嗎？
-Go meet him then. -Can I do that?
-那就去見他吧 -可以嗎？
Then I'll be back in an hour.
我一小時後回來
My gosh.
天哪
Damn! There's caramel on my clothes.
該死！我的衣服上有焦糖
-Nyudo. You did this, huh? -So noisy…
-入道，是你幹的吧？ -吵死了
Disgusting! Give me my clothes!
好噁心！把我的衣服拿來！
-What are you looking at? -I wasn't looking.
-你看什麼？ -我沒看
Yes, you were. Just now.
你剛剛看了
Oh, goodness. Finally, we have some space.
天哪，終於沒那麼擁擠了
-It's a demon. There's a demon here. -What kind?
-是妖怪，這裡有妖怪 -什麼樣的妖怪？
-A mermaid. -Doesn't mermaid flesh grant immortality?
-人魚 -吃人魚肉可以長生不老吧？
I want to eat it.
我想吃
Yuki, I'll catch it for you.
宥淇，我幫妳去抓
That's enough. The mission comes first for now.
夠了，現在最要緊的是任務
Yum! It's so delicious.
嗯，太好吃了！
You look free. Aren't you going to catch Red-white mask?
你好像很閒，不去抓紅白面具人嗎？
I already went looking for him, but he's gone.
我去找過他，但他不見了
-Want my guys to look for him? -No. He'll come on his own.
-要我派手下去找他嗎？ -不用，他會自己回來的
You will die before you live a century.
你活不到一百年
In the year 2020, you sacrifice yourself on your brother's behalf.
2020年，你會為你哥哥犧牲自己
How are things with the mermaid? Is it going well?
你和人魚怎麼樣了？進展順利嗎？
-I hear you see her daily. -Not daily.
-聽說你們天天見面 -不是天天
Let's set a date for us to meet. Where should we meet?
選個日子，大家一起見面訂婚吧 應該約在哪裡呢？
Korean cuisine or Western cuisine? Seafood's off the table, right?
吃韓餐還是西餐？海鮮肯定不行吧？
-The bride is a similar species after all. -Are you crazy? Engagement, my foot.
-畢竟是新娘的近親 -你瘋了嗎？訂什麼婚
-My wish is to see you get married. -That's none of your business.
-看你結婚是我的心願 -不要你管
Hey! Why are you drinking makgeolli on an empty stomach, huh?
喂，幹嘛空腹喝馬格利酒？
-Here. Have some suyuk too. -Seriously, cut it out.
-來，吃點白切肉 -真是的，別鬧了
-Is this so upsetting to you, huh? -Stop being nice. It's annoying.
-這張臉讓你很不爽嗎？ -不要對我這麼好，很煩
What's the problem this time, huh? Why are you being perverse?
這次又怎麼了？在鬧什麼脾氣？
Hey!
喂！
Geez, that little…
真是的，臭小子
Gosh, that brat. We haven't even much time left together.
這個小混蛋 我們在一起的時間已經不多了
Akira!
阿亮！
Didn't you want to see Yuki?
你不想見宥淇嗎？
-I'm not so sure. -Yuki missed Akira so, so much.
-不太想 -宥淇好想阿亮呢
I heard you got bitch-slapped by Joseon demons.
聽說你被朝鮮妖怪扇耳光
Don't laugh!
不要笑！
I'll get you your revenge.
我會幫你報仇的
Just do as you're told.
聽命行事就好
Don't give Yuki orders!
不准你命令宥淇！
Akira, you sure look dapper now since quitting the group?
阿亮，退出兵團後 你確實變得衣冠楚楚了
Is it 'cause it's a white-collar job?
因為這是白領工作嗎？
Don't touch me.
不要碰我
You came.
你們來了
Shinigami Mercenaries. Arriving from Manchuria.
死神僱傭兵團，從滿洲前來報到
Everyone, thank you for your efforts in battle.
感謝各位在戰鬥中的辛苦付出
-Where's your boss? -You haven't seen him?
-你們團長呢？ -您還沒見到他嗎？
-He left for Gyeongseong before us. -Boss only shows up when he feels like it.
-他先我們一步來了京城 -老大只會隨心所欲地現身
Just tell us the mission. I might lose my mind from impatience.
有任務就吩咐吧 我可能會因為失去耐心而發狂
-We're conducting an experiment. -An experiment?
-我們要進行一項試驗 -試驗？
To convert Joseon demons into the Empire's war weapons.
把朝鮮妖怪變成帝國的作戰武器
Oh, my. That sounds like so much fun.
天哪，聽起來超有趣的
Your mission is to capture the Joseon demons.
你們的任務是抓捕朝鮮妖怪
Can I kill them and bring back only a body part?
殺死他們，帶回部分殘肢可以嗎？
It'll be difficult to capture them alive.
活捉他們並不容易
And how will you be paying?
您要如何酬謝我們？
By the number of heads.
按數量付費
Yes, sir!
是！
Was it a good idea to call them?
叫他們來沒問題嗎？
-They move arbitrarily. -The experiments aren't everything.
-他們向來任意妄為 -並不全是為了試驗
We must wipe them out.
我們必須把他們清除乾淨
Uproot the Joseon demons, and their folk beliefs.
根除朝鮮妖怪及其民間信仰
We must uproot the spirit of Joseon.
我們必須根除朝鮮精神
-I looked into the one named Lee Yeon. -And?
-我查過那個名叫李硯的妖怪 -然後呢？
He's at Myoyeongak.
他在妙緣閣
Just like the Madame, he's also a mountain god of Joseon.
他和閣長一樣，也是朝鮮山神
A mountain god of Joseon, you say.
是朝鮮山神啊
It was a long wait.
久等了
-Old man. -Yeah.
-老頭子 -是我
-How did you find me? -You weren't home, so…
-你是如何找到我的？ -你不在家，所以…
-Isn't your brother buried here? -Yes, he used to be.
-你哥哥不是葬在這裡嗎？ -以前是
But he's there now.
現在他在那裡
Moo-yeong, what on earth are you trying to do?
無影，你究竟想做什麼？
I'm boiling his bones with dirt. Plus, a weasel, snake, and spider.
我要熬他的屍骨，混上泥土 還有黃鼠狼、蛇和蜘蛛各一隻
Don't tell me…
該不會是…
Do you intend to work the banhon charm? No, you can't. You mustn't wreck…
你想使用返魂術？ 不行，你千萬不能破壞…
BANHON CHARM - CHARM THAT REVIVES THE DEAD
（返魂術：起死回生的法術）
-…the realm of the Living and the Dead. -I know. I may never be forgiven for it.
-…陰陽兩界 -我知道，我可能罪無可赦
-But I have to do it. -Don't turn the old hag into your enemy.
-但我必須這樣做 -不要逼老妖婆與你為敵
Neither she nor I… We haven't given up on you.
她和我都沒有…我們還沒有放棄你
This is why I didn't want to see you.
所以我才不想見你
You kept my company even when I became stone.
即便我變成石柱，你也陪伴著我
When it was snowing, you'd put clothes on an immobile piece of stone.
遇到下雪天 你還幫不會動的石柱披上衣服
You were always sensitive to the cold.
你向來怕冷
I'm no longer the Moo-yeong you knew. No. I must not be.
我已經不是你認識的無影了 不對，我不能再做從前的自己
Moo-yeong, you think I don't know you?
無影，你以為我不瞭解你嗎？
Just let me be the villain.
就讓我當那個壞人吧
Don't come looking for me anymore.
不要再來找我了
I bought this for you.
我帶了這個給你
Don't skip meals.
按時吃飯
-When are you leaving? -I have less than a week left.
-你什麼時候走？ -還有不到一週時間
-Do you have to go? -Yes, I do.
-非走不可嗎？ -沒錯
I have someone waiting.
有人在等我
Geez, you jerk.
混蛋
I heard she was reincarnated? That woman.
聽說她轉世了？那個女人
Moo-yeong tell you that?
無影告訴妳的？
Why didn't you say anything about Moo-yeong's identity?
妳為什麼不告訴我無影的身份？
You knew, didn't you?
妳早就知道吧？
Perhaps, I hoped to dream.
也許我想要做夢
That maybe we could return to the old days.
夢想著我們還能回到從前
Just a silly dream that only I have.
只有我會做這個傻乎乎的夢
I don't know if you'll believe me, but I never abandoned either of you.
我不知道妳信不信 但我從來沒有拋棄過妳或他
That's why I can't forgive him.
這也是我無法原諒他的原因
I'll end this with my own hands.
我要親手結束這一切
You're just like him.
你和他都一樣
You both risk your lives to save me…
你們都會冒著生命危險來救我
yet steal each other from me again.
卻又再次從我身邊奪走對方
I'm sorry, Hong-joo.
對不起，紅酒
For never giving you the answer you wanted.
我從未能給妳想要的答案
But I have something to protect.
但是我有想要守護的東西
Both here, and the future where I'm from.
這裡有，未來也有
Fine, then. If that's how you guys want to be.
好，你們想怎樣就怎樣吧
I quit being the pathetic damsel in distress.
我不會再做可憐的遇險少女了
I, too, will do whatever it takes to protect Myoyeongak and my girls.
我也會不惜一切代價 守護妙緣閣和我手下的女孩
You left one out.
妳漏掉了一個人
You. Be sure to protect yourself too.
妳自己，也要守護好自己才行
I want a hug.
抱我一下
I won't play fair from now.
從現在起，我要不擇手段了
SAFETY AND SECURITY SAY NO TO WAR
（安全保障，決死抗戰）
Wait! Hold on!
等等！等一下！
I mean, this isn't a barbershop. It's useless if we do this ourselves.
這裡又不是理髮店 我們自己剃頭有什麼用！
We must get Taluipa to come out! The Talui-- Hey, hey!
必須叫奪衣婆出來！奪…喂！
-You should be fasting right now. -Geez.
-你應該絕食的 -天哪
-Hey! -This is why-- Oh, gosh.
-喂！ -所以說…天哪
Oh, my.
哎呦
Now you decide to show your face?
妳終於決定露面了？
I'm here to watch the sedentary deity shave his head.
我是來看主大監神剃頭的
SEDENTARY DEITY - A HOUSE-PROTECTING TUTELARY DEITY
（主大監神：保護家宅的守護神）
Well, I don't know.
話說回來
If I bid farewell to my hair, I expect it'll make things tougher on you.
如果我剃了髮 妳要承受更大的痛苦才行
Go for it. You have a nice shaped head.
剃吧，你的頭型長得不錯
-Should I cut it-- -Gosh! Hold on! Geez.
-要不要剪… -真是的！等一下！
Let me knock some sense into you.
我要把妳打清醒
Wait, wait-- Hold on! Let's talk! We'll settle this with words.
別這樣，等等！有話好好說！
You might die if you keep this up!
這樣下去，你可能會沒命的！
Whose side are you on?
你站在哪一邊？
The indigenous gods have been disappearing for no reason.
本土神一直在無故失蹤
-We don't have a place to live right now. -So?
-如今，我們已無棲身之處了 -所以呢？
What? You want me to buy you a house?
怎樣？要我幫你們買房子嗎？
Oh, honey. It's a matter of their survival.
老婆，這關係到他們的生存
Our job is to oversee life and death, not to look after these pricks!
我們的職責是監管生死 而不是照顧這些混帳！
You see this? I knew this would happen!
看到了吧？我就知道會這樣！
If this problem remains unresolved,
如果這個問題得不到解決
know that all the provincial gods will gather here to go on strike!
外地神也會聚集到這裡罷工的！
-Destroy him first! -Oh, no.
-先處死他！ -不要啊
Come on, honey. Don't be like that. Let's help them out however we can.
拜託了，老婆，不要這樣嘛 我們盡量幫幫他們吧
Honey, drag all those pricks out of here.
老公，把這些混帳拖出去
And do as I say.
嚴格按照我的吩咐做
It's a demon. There's a disguised demon.
是妖怪，有一個偽裝成人的妖怪
It's original form?
本體是什麼？
One is an eagle-owl, and the other is a nine-tailed fox.
一個是鵰鴞，另一個是九尾狐
Hey, hey! He's super cute!
等等！他超帥的！
That man! To think such a beautiful demon was in Joseon.
那個男人！ 朝鮮竟然有如此好看的妖怪
-Don't touch him. I'll take care of it. -Yuki!
-不要碰他，我去搞定他 -宥淇！
-Gosh, what! -You can't.
-天哪，幹嘛！ -妳不能去
Here.
給妳
Gosh, you sure are a fox.
天哪，果然是狐狸
What are you, a girl? Slapping all that on your face.
你是不是男人啊？ 往臉上塗那麼多東西
Says the guy slapping oil on his sheets. Want to fight again?
你還往被子上抹油呢，又想打架嗎？
You little--
臭小子…
Both of you. Let's talk for a minute.
兩位，我們談談吧
We're sharing rooms due to inevitable circumstances,
因為不得已的情況 我們得分享一個房間
but communal life entails responsibility.
但是共同生活是需要承擔責任的
I can't sleep because of you two fighting!
你們兩個吵得我睡不著！
-Just last night-- -This thief used my chamber pot.
-昨晚還… -這個小偷用了我的夜壺
We shared some potty pan, so what's the big deal? Geez.
我們共用便盆 有什麼大不了的？真是的
You should at least not poop in someone else's chamber pot!
你至少不該在別人的夜壺裡大便吧！
-Why not? -Let me tell you the rules of this room.
-為什麼不行？ -我來宣佈這個房間的規矩
First, don't fight after 9 p.m.
第一，晚上九點後禁止吵架
Second, live a regular lifestyle. We wake up at six in the morning.
第二，正常作息，早上六點起床
-What? Is this the military? -Third, take turns cleaning once a day.
-什麼？這是部隊嗎？ -第三，每天輪流打掃一次衛生
-Be sure to hang your sheets in the sun. -Gosh, you sure do nag a lot.
-一定要晾曬床單 -天哪，你這個人好嘮叨
May I ask what you are behind your disguise?
我能問問你的本體是什麼嗎？
I'm a Jindo.
我是珍島犬
Natural monument no. 53.
自然紀念物編號53
THE JINDO WAS DESIGNATED AS A NATURAL MONUMENT IN 1938
（1938年 珍島犬被指定為自然紀念物）
Paw.
爪爪
Don't do that!
不要這樣！
We're an endangered species too, you know.
你要知道，我們也是瀕危物種
Bang!
砰！
Usually, dogs play dead if I do this.
一般情況下，狗狗都會裝死的
-Bang!
-砰！
Do you two…
你們…
wish to go extinct?
想要絕種嗎？
Water. Water!
水！
Eat up.
多吃點
Gosh, seriously.
真是的
You want us to resolve all those civil complaints? Why?
你要我們解決 所有的民事投訴？為什麼？
You have no choice. You refuse, you can't go home and you're going to hell.
你們別無選擇，一旦拒絕 你便回不了家，而妳要下地獄
-Seriously, this old hag-- -I get him, but why me?
-真是的，這個老妖婆… -他也就算了，為什麼是我？
She commuted your jail sentence for killing that salt merchant, no?
妳殺死那個鹽商後 她有幫妳減刑吧？
-I knew it. -I actually bribed her for that. One cow!
-我就知道 -我賄賂過她的，一頭牛！
Whatever, I don't know! Anyway, I'm leaving her to you.
不管了，我不知道！ 總之，我把她交給你了
-Old man, how can you leave like this? -Old man!
-老頭子，你怎麼能一走了之？ -老頭子！
Gosh.
天哪
Whatever, you take care of it. It's your house.
妳去處理吧，這是妳家
Let's do it together. Sheesh!
一起去吧！
Stop eating!
別吃了！
No cutting in line!
不要插隊！
Hey, stand in line!
喂，排隊啊！
Hey!
喂！
Attention, everyone.
大家請注意
We made kimchi today, so we're exhausted. I'd like to avoid violence, if possible.
我們今天做了泡菜，已經很累了 我想盡量避免使用暴力
-So let's keep this neat. -Come in one at a time.
-請大家遵守秩序 -一個一個來
Make your story short and brief. Within a 20 word count.
簡單說明情況，不能超過二十字
-Who are you and where are you from? -I own the well by that intersection.
-妳是誰？從哪裡來的？ -我是十字路口那口井的主人
A well god? What brings you here?
井神嗎？妳有什麼事？
WELL GOD - AN INDIGENOUS GOD WHO STOPS WELLS FROM DRYING OUT
（井神：防止水井乾涸的本土神）
My well produces medicinal water.
我的井水具有藥效
People all the way from Incheon to draw water from it.
人們不惜從仁川千里迢迢來取水
But they say it tastes different now.
但是他們說水的味道不一樣了
You think we're here to replace your water purifier filters?
妳以為我們是來幫妳更換 淨水過濾器的嗎？
-What's a water purifier? -You want to clean the well or move out?
-淨水過濾器是什麼？ -妳想清理水井還是想搬走？
Gosh, I can't use that well anymore.
天哪，我不能再用那口井了
Someone put chemicals in the water, so I need a new place to nest.
有人在井裡放入化學物質 我們必須換個地方安家
Then, find her an unclaimed well and let her nest there.
幫她找一口無主的水井 讓她在那裡安家
Next!
下一位！
I'm the crock god, and my crock jar was stolen.
我是凸隆神，我的瓦罐被盜了
I don't know who did it, but I hear they were dressed like Japanese soldiers.
不知道是誰幹的 但我聽說他們的裝束像日本兵
Maybe they were stolen because the crock god left his post.
也許是因為凸隆神擅離職守 瓦罐才會被盜吧？
CROCK GOD - AN INDIGENOUS GOD WHO PROTECTS CROCK JARS
（凸隆神：保護瓦罐的本土神）
-You're right. -Why did you go wandering around?
-沒錯 -你為什麼到處亂跑？
I gained some weight so the jar felt a little tight.
我長胖了，瓦罐裡有點擠
-Buy him one. -Yes, ma'am.
-給他買一個瓦罐 -遵命
Well, might as well buy me quality earthen pots from Yeoju--
順便幫我買一個驪州瓦鍋吧
Get out of here!
給我滾蛋！
Who are you?
妳是誰？
Oh, dear.
天哪
Why? What is it?
幹嘛？怎麼了？
She's the ancestral god.
她是帝釋神
Her landlord doesn't hold ancestral rites, so she's famished.
她的屋主不供奉帝釋 所以她快要餓死了
ANCESTRAL GOD - A GOD WHO PROTECTS
（帝釋神）
ONE'S DESCENDANTS
（保佑後代的神）
-Is that something to whisper about? -She's a bit shy.
-這有必要講悄悄話嗎？ -她有點腼腆
-So what does she want? -She wishes to demolish her house.
-那她想怎樣？ -她想拆除那棟房子
This is the problem with tutelary deities. You guys don't own the house, okay?
這就是守護神的問題 房子的主人不是你們，知道嗎？
You share it with the descendants. Like "home sharing."
要和屋主的後代同住才行 等於是“共享房屋”
Feed her ritual leftovers and send her off.
拿供奉儀式的剩菜餵飽她 打發她走吧
Next.
下一位
He's the Great General of all Under Heaven placed below Bukhansan.
他是北漢山下的天下大將軍
But the Female General of the Underworld, has gone missing.
但是冥界女將軍失蹤了
-Oh, dear. -You hit the boredom rut.
-天哪 -因為你們的日子太無聊吧
Next!
下一位！
-I'm home. -Where have you been off to lately?
-我回來了 -妳最近跑到哪裡去了？
Maybe my dad's forgotten, but I'm a journalist.
爸爸可能忘了，我是新聞記者
A reporter at my newspaper company.
我報社的記者
And your boss is telling you to sit down.
老闆命令妳坐下
I'm not hungry.
我不餓
Your dad's worried you've lost weight.
妳瘦了，爸爸很擔心妳
The daughter of Gyeongseong's richest man looking like barley hump
堂堂京城首富的女兒瘦到弱不禁風
will have me become a laughingstock.
會讓我成為別人的笑柄
-Ginko is just busy. -What do you know about me?
-銀子只是太忙了 -你又不瞭解我
Why you brat. How rude! He's even brought you a present.
臭丫頭，沒禮貌！ 他還給妳帶了禮物呢
What for?
什麼禮物？
Look at it alone.
妳一個人看吧
Since I've already been robbed, let's just fund our war chest.
既然我被打劫了 就用它資助我們的戰爭吧
Why does the Chief Commissioner have this?
這東西怎麼會在首席專員手中？
I'm sure I gave it to a member of the organization.
我明明交給組織裡的一位成員了
Well? Do you like it?
怎麼樣？喜歡嗎？
What kind of present is it?
是什麼禮物呢？
-Why are you giving this to me? -We're family.
-為什麼送我這個？ -我們是一家人
I'm always keeping an eye on you, Ginko.
銀子，我一直都在關注妳
What can you even do with this?
你能把我怎麼樣？
You need my family background, no?
你需要依附我家的勢力，不是嗎？
You are where you are thanks to that.
你能有今天也是因為這個原因
CLUB PARADISE
（樂園俱樂部）
Thank goodness.
謝天謝地
Your heart is beating, and you're breathing just fine.
心跳有力，呼吸正常
You're alive, my brother.
我的弟弟還活著
Please hang in there until I get back.
請你堅持住，等我回來
I will never give up on you.
我永遠都不會放棄你
Stay with me for the next month.
接下來一個月和我一起住吧
Then take me, not Cheon Moo-yeong.
那你帶我去，不要帶千無影
I can go with anyone, but you! How could I send you to your death!
我帶誰去都可以，只有你不行！ 我怎麼可以讓你去送死！
I had a rough idea.
我大概明白了
Because during our time together…
我們在一起的時間裡…
he was getting ready to leave.
他已經做好了離開的準備
Eat. You should gain some weight.
吃吧，你應該長胖一點
Do I have to tuck you in?
還要我幫你蓋被子嗎？
But…
可是…
He did all that out of guilt.
他做的一切都是因為愧疚
I will…
我會…
die because of Lee Yeon.
因為李硯而死去
Now that I think about it…
現在想起來…
I have nowhere to return to.
我已經無處可去了
I still have more songs to sing.
我還有幾首歌要唱
I don't need this.
我不需要打傘
-Did something bad happen? -Don't follow me for pity's sake.
-是不是發生什麼事情了？ -拜託妳行行好，不要跟著我
Who is it? Who upset you? Tell me and I'll take care of it.
是誰惹你生氣了？告訴我，我去處理
-Rang-- -Stop it!
-阿朗… -別煩我！
Are you mad at me?
你是在生我的氣嗎？
Or do you need someone to vent to?
還是說，你需要找個人發洩？
Yes, I'm upset because of you.
對，我生氣是因為妳
What did I do wrong?
我做錯什麼了？
After being abandoned by my parents and my brother,
被父母和哥哥拋棄後
I wandered alone for hundreds of years.
我獨自流浪了數百年
I…
我…
I'm just a stain in their lives.
我只是他們生命中的一個污點
I was pissed, I started killing humans.
我滿心怨氣，開始殺害人類
I became a bandit to loot and set fire to things.
變成一個燒殺搶掠的土匪
That was my normal.
那才是我的常態
But…
可是…
But what?
可是什麼？
You. All of you.
妳，你們所有人
You all keep making me weak. It's annoying.
你們總是讓我軟弱下來，好討厭
I keep feeling tickles over here.
我這裡總是忍不住開心
The world wasn't so bad to live in.
覺得活在這世上也不錯
It was warm. Even to someone like me.
即使是我這樣的人，也能感受到溫暖
I hate feeling such pathetic feelings.
我討厭這種可憐兮兮的感覺
So? What's your conclusion?
所以呢？你的結論是什麼？
I…
我…
I don't need anyone anymore.
我已經不需要任何人了
Neither you nor Lee Yeon.
包括妳、李硯
Or the bandit gang.
還有土匪幫
You coward.
你這個懦夫
-What? -Neglecting is always the easiest.
-什麼？ -忽視是最偷懶的辦法
Breaking up and forgetting, all on your own.
單方面決定分手、忘記對方
Stop using the world's easiest shield.
不要再用最偷懶的辦法當擋箭牌了
Face your fears like the boss of a bandit gang!
拿出土匪幫頭目的氣概來 面對你的恐懼吧！
What the hell do you know? Who do you think you are?
妳懂什麼？妳以為妳是誰？
I'm not unimportant, and I'm not being careless.
我不是無名小卒，也沒有無憂無慮
We kissed.
我們親吻過
And I'm going to marry you.
我還打算嫁給你呢
So you can't run away anymore.
所以你不能再逃跑了
Everyone, we're calling it a day. Come tomorrow if you haven't had your say!
各位，今天就到這裡吧 還沒有機會發言的人明天再來！
-What? -Huh?
-什麼？ -啊？
-But isn't it a bit strange? -What is?
-妳不覺得有點奇怪嗎？ -什麼？
I think someone's after the tutelary deities.
我覺得有人盯上了這些守護神
So many of them suddenly disappeared.
所以他們之中很多人都突然消失了
I ordered Jae-yoo to look into something.
我命令載宇去調查了一件事
-You know that raccoon couple? -Damn, how could I not?
-你知道那對浣熊夫婦吧？ -該死，怎麼會不知道？
They recently got kidnapped in an alley.
他們最近在一條巷子裡遭人綁架
Kidnapped? By whom?
綁架？是誰幹的？
Orders from the Governor-General. Chief Commissioner, Ryuhei Kato.
總督下的命令，首席專員加藤龍平
He's running some experiment.
他在進行某種試驗
Kato. Where have I heard that name?
加藤，我在哪裡聽過這個名字？
My name is Ryuhei Kato. Remember it. We'll meet again.
我叫加藤龍平 記住這個名字，我們還會見面的
It's that guy!
是那個傢伙！
Shall I destroy it? The Governor-General of Korea.
要我除掉那個大韓總督嗎？
If you kill them, what happens then?
殺死他們又能怎樣？
A new Governor. A new Chief Commissioner will come.
會有新的總督、新的首席專員上任
I'll fight them too!
我會繼續對抗他們！
Who will? You have less than a week left, no?
誰去對抗？你剩不到一週了吧？
Don't forget that you're merely an uninvited guest in this era.
別忘了，你只是這個時代的不速之客
Can I just put these on?
我能直接穿上這套衣服嗎？
I'll deduct it from my salary.
我會把衣服的錢從薪水裡扣掉
Were you always this rough-spoken?
妳講話一直都這麼粗魯嗎？
Don't stop me. I'll be Mrs. Bandit Gang soon.
不要阻止我，我很快就是土匪夫人了
Don't marry me.
不要嫁給我
-Why not? -If I die, you'll be left alone.
-為什麼？ -若我死了，妳就剩自己一人了
You're not going to. I'll fight the Grim Reaper.
你不會死的，我會打敗死神
How reassuring.
那我就放心了
Where should we go for our honeymoon? The mountain or the sea?
我們要去哪裡度蜜月呢？ 山間還是海邊？
Shall we go to both?
兩個都去怎麼樣？
Let's go to Mt. Geumgang first.
我們先去金剛山吧
They say not to discuss scenery without seeing Mt. Geumgang.
聽說沒去過金剛山的人 沒有資格談論美景
After that, let's go to the East Sea.
然後我們再去東海
You will die before you live a century.
你活不到一百年
In the year 2020, you sacrifice yourself on your brother's behalf.
2020年，你會為你哥哥犧牲自己
You smell the blood, huh?
聞到血腥味了吧？
Don't rush me.
不要急
Once I finish this, I'll get you some food.
等我完成儀式，就去幫你找吃的
-Wait! Move. -Let go!
-等等！讓開 -放手！
Move, you bastard!
讓開，混蛋！
Wh-- Darn it.
該死
Gosh, that's refreshing.
天哪，超爽的
Hey--
喂
Hey!
喂！
Move!
讓開！
That prick!
那個混蛋！
Man, that felt good.
天哪，太舒服了
Gosh, my shoulder.
哎呦，我的肩膀
Is it from making kimchi?
是因為醃泡菜太累了嗎？
-You too? -The clams we had for dinner
-你也來了？ -我們晚飯吃的蛤蜊
must've been spoiled.
肯定壞掉了
Will this help with the smell?
這樣可以除臭吧？
-Just this once. -All right, let's go.
-就一次 -好，來吧
-Let's go. -If you win this one…
-來吧 -如果你這次贏了…
That's right.
沒錯
Come on in, come on.
來吧…
There it comes!
來了！
Want to play a game?
想玩一局嗎？
I'll pass.
不了
How much is on the line?
賭多少錢？
They're not playing for money.
他們不賭錢
This is the Dokgakgwi's game, after all.
畢竟這是獨腳鬼的賭局
That man is the Dokgakgwi?
那個人是獨腳鬼？
If not money, then what?
不賭錢賭什麼？
DOKGAKGWI - AN ANCIENT WORD FOR GOBLIN
（獨腳鬼：對小妖精的古稱）
Life span.
壽命
Go Dokgakgwi! Go Dokgakgwi!
獨腳鬼加油！
I heard Jae-yoo fell into the the toilet.
我聽說載宇掉進茅廁了
Serves him right for being a germophobe.
活該，誰叫他有潔癖
You sit, and make some poo tteok.
坐下來做一些糞糕吧
What's a poo tteok?
是什麼糞糕？
POO TTEOK - WARDS OFF MISFORTUNE WHEN SOMEONE FALLS IN THE TOILET
（糞糕：幫掉入茅廁的人 驅除惡運的食物）
It blocks off misfortune. Even great shamans
它可以驅除惡運 即便是最厲害的巫師
can't treat illnesses from falling in toilets.
也治不好因為掉進茅廁而病倒的人
Try-- Try this.
嚐嚐這個
Eat as many as your age.
你多少歲就吃多大个的糕
Man, it stinks.
天哪，臭死了
He's not just a dog anymore. He's a poop dog now.
他已經不是普通的狗了，他是糞狗
Please don't tell Madame Ryu. I beg you.
拜託你不要告訴柳閣長，求求你
Hang tight.
你放心
It may not seem like it, but I'm known for being tight-lipped.
別看我這樣 我這個人出了名的口風緊
He fell in the toilet? How?
他掉進茅廁了？怎麼會？
According to him, someone pulled him down from below.
他是說有人從下面拽他下去
He's too ashamed to tell the truth.
他不好意思講實話
The point is, he's stinking up the room. So if you will grant us another room--
問題是整個房間都被他熏臭了 請閣長幫我們安排一個新房間…
You.
你
Shut up and take the lead.
閉嘴，帶路
-Close it. -Close it? Okay.
-關門 -關門？好
-My goodness! -Open it.
-天哪！ -開門
I'm scared. Do I open-- I'll open it.
我害怕，開…我開
-Don't come in! -Yeah, I won't.
-別進來！ -我不會進去的
-Oh, geez! -What?
-真是的！ -幹嘛？
What's this?
這是什麼？
What's what? It's filth straight from the toilet.
還用問嗎？ 當然是茅廁裡掏出來的穢物
Get hit, you get jinxed.
被打中會倒霉的
Quite the temper, huh?
妳的脾氣不小啊？
-You're the toilet god, aren't you? -A toilet god?
-妳是廁神吧？ -廁神？
They say evil mistresses become toilet gods after they die.
據說惡婦死後會變成廁神
So it's true.
原來是真的
-What the hell are you doing? -Just let her be.
-妳在幹嘛？ -別管她
She'll only be satisfied when she finishes counting your hair.
她要數完你的頭髮才能滿意
Damn it. I lost count because of you, wench!
該死，妳害我數錯了，死丫頭！
Wench?
死丫頭？
All right, let's get started.
好了，開始吧
Let's see, let's see.
我看看
LEE RANG - 82 YEARS OF LIFE SPAN
（李朗：壽命八十二年）
DOKGAKGWI - 963 YEARS OF LIFE SPAN
（獨腳鬼：壽命九百六十三年）
-I can't watch this. -Seriously.
-我真不忍看下去 -真是的
-There it is, there! -You poor boy.
-有了！ -你這個可憐的小子
All right.
好吧
I bet 50 years.
我押五十年
-Call. Show me your hand. -Yours first.
-我跟，亮牌吧 -你先亮牌
Pair of threes.
兩張三點
-He got pair of fives! -I win!
-他有兩張五點！ -我贏了！
Dokgakgwi wins!
獨腳鬼贏了！
As expected of Lord Dokgakgwi!
不愧是獨腳鬼大人！
Give me your 50 years.
你的五十年壽命歸我了
-One more game. -Wait.
-再賭一局 -等等
Oh, it's heavy. Here, sir.
好重啊，大人，給你
Let me have my night snack.
我要吃宵夜
Memilmuk, my love.
蕎麥凍，我的最愛
Oh, wow! Give me a bite.
哇！給我吃一口吧
It's mine!
這是我的！
-A lump! -He has a lump.
-腫塊！ -他長腫塊了
He got a lump!
他長出一顆腫塊了
Next round.
下一局
All right, fine.
好啊
Here we go.
來吧
What are you doing in my house?
妳在我家做什麼？
When I arrived, I didn't see any house deities here so…
我來的時候 看到這裡沒有家神，所以…
So you were planning to nest in our toilet?
妳打算在我們的茅廁裡安家嗎？
Why did you pull Jae-yoo in?
為什麼把載宇拽下去？
He brought me flowers at night.
他夜裡送我花
It'd been ages, since I'd gotten flowers from a man.
我很多年沒收到男人送的花了
So I wanted to spend eternity with him.
所以我想生生世世和他在一起
I support this love.
我支持這段愛情
-Cut the nonsense. Get lost! -Yes, ma'am.
-不准胡說，滾蛋！ -是
You too!
妳也滾蛋！
Wait! Will you allow me to nest in here?
等等！我可以在這裡安家嗎？
Don't try to play me. I hate tutelary deities.
別想騙我，我討厭守護神
You bless, you curse. I know how fickle you all are. Just go.
想保佑就保佑，想詛咒就詛咒 我知道你們有多善變，快滾
Wait!
等一下！
If you let me nest here, I'll tell you about the treasure.
如果妳允許我在這裡安家 我就告訴妳寶物的事
The treasure?
寶物？
I heard it from the house deities of the gold mining royalties.
是金礦開採家族的家神告訴我的
That the Baekdudaegan mountains god has the guardian stone and golden ruler.
守護石和金尺 在白頭大幹山的山神手中
What?
什麼？
Boss' brother! We have bad news!
老大的哥哥！不好了！
What is it again?
又怎麼了？
Boss is on a betting gamble!
老大跟人賭博了！
Man, he's addicted.
天哪，他簡直上癮了
-How much has he lost? -It isn't money. That's not it.
-輸掉多少錢？ -不是錢，不是錢的問題
Over here, here.
在這裡
Hey.
喂
What happened?
你怎麼了？
It's my remaining life span.
這是我剩餘的壽命
I've less than a day to live.
還剩不到一天的時間
Who did this to you?
是誰把你害成這樣的？
-A pair of tens! -Yes!
-兩張十點！ -好！
You rude bastard!
你這個無禮的混蛋！
Shut up and revert what you did to my brother.
閉嘴，把我弟弟的壽命還回來
Your brother?
弟弟？
The nine-tailed fox from earlier?
之前那隻九尾狐嗎？
Dokgakgwi won them.
那是獨腳鬼贏來的
Give it back.
還給我
What makes you think you can take my brother's scant life span?
你憑什麼認為你能隨便奪走 我弟弟所剩不多的壽命？
A bet is a bet.
願賭服輸
I'll kill you.
我要殺了你
Why don't you try?
你試試看啊？
Let's see if that'll bring his life span back.
看你弟弟的壽命會不會變回去
Assertive as always, sir!
大人依舊這麼自信！
Lord Dokgakgwi is never scared.
獨腳鬼大人從來不害怕
Come on. Let's see you try.
來啊，動手啊
Hurry up and stab me. Go on.
快來刺死我，來吧
What do you want?
你想怎樣？
I'll give you anything you want, so revert his life span.
我什麼都可以給你，恢復他的壽命吧
Really? Then gamble against me.
真的？那就跟我賭
You can beat me and win his life span back, right?
賭贏我就能贏回他的壽命，對吧？
I don't gamble.
我不賭博
Then it can't be helped.
那就沒辦法了
-Let's set up for another game! -Yes, sir. Set the table!
-我們再賭一局！ -是，大人，擺局！
Quickly, quick.
快點
Boss, what do I do? What will happen to you?
老大，怎麼辦？你會發生什麼事？
Quit being noisy.
別吵了
You can lead the gang when I'm gone.
等我不在了，你做土匪幫老大吧
Boss, don't die. We promised to take all of Gyeongseong!
老大，不要死 我們說好了要拿下京城的！
Stop whining.
別抱怨了
Do me a favor.
幫我個忙
Why did you do that?
你為什麼要這樣做？
Why risk your life on a stupid bet?
為什麼為一個愚蠢的賭局拿命冒險？
It's my life.
命是我的
Who cares what I do with it.
我拿它怎樣又有誰在意
You pathetic bastard.
你這個無可救藥的混蛋
You take responsibility for your own actions.
你自己的行為自己負責
You're finally showing your true colors.
你終於露出真面目了
-Fine, this is you after all. -You get sick and hurt day in, day out.
-也對，你就是這樣 -你一天到晚不是生病就是受傷
And now you go so far as to lose your own life span?
現在居然連壽命都弄丟了？
How much longer must I clean up after you?
還要我幫你收拾爛攤子多久？
It's your fault!
都怪你！
It's you who made me this way.
是你害我變成這樣的
Why are you acting like this? Huh?
你為什麼要這樣？
Please, can't you just live a decent life?
拜託，你就不能好好生活嗎？
How am I supposed to leave now? Damn it.
現在叫我怎麼放心離開？真是的
-Hey. -Geez.
-喂 -天哪
You're crying? Because of me?
你哭了？因為我嗎？
-I wasn't crying! -I didn't want to die!
-我沒有哭！ -我不想死！
I, too, wanted to live.
我也想活下去
You…
你…
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
You would know better, no?
你最清楚了，不是嗎？
Lord Lee Yeon is gambling with his life span!
李硯大人要拿自己的壽命去賭博了！
-Begin. -Before we do that,
-開始 -開始之前
I must check how much you have.
我必須查看你的壽命
Fifty-two years? You're kidding?
五十二年？開什麼玩笑？
What kind of mountain god has this little?
哪有這麼短命的山神？
When I have this much.
我的壽命可長著呢
I decided to die on the same day as a human woman.
我已經下定決心 和一個人類女人死在同一天了
-Pathetic bastard. -Fine.
-可悲的混蛋 -好吧
Give him 52 candles.
給他五十二支蠟燭
What an embarrassing amount.
這個數目少得可憐
All right, I bet 10 years.
好，我押十年
Call.
我跟
Show me.
亮牌
It's a high seven.
一張七點
-I got a high nine! -That's right!
-我的是九點！ -沒錯！
As expected!
果然厲害！
Dokgakgwi! Dokgakgwi!
獨腳鬼！
That's 10 years off your life span.
你要減掉十年壽命
All right. I bet 12 years.
好，我押十二年
Here we go.
亮牌
Pair of ones.
兩張一點
Pair of twos!
兩張兩點！
-That's right! -All right!
-沒錯！ -太好了！
Dokgakgwi is better at cards than a mountain god. How's that?
獨腳鬼的牌技勝過山神！厲害吧？
You feeling all jittery?
是不是緊張了？
What? Did you just laugh?
什麼？你是在笑嗎？
Fine, then.
那好吧
Do you want to shuffle?
你想洗牌嗎？
Oh, goodness. Looks like he's never gambled before.
天哪，看來他是第一次賭博
You're risking your life span with such petty skills?
雕蟲小技居然敢拿壽命冒險？
-Exactly my point! -Guess we're holding a funeral today.
-就是嘛！ -看來我們今天要辦喪事了
-Oh, my goodness. -What a pity.
-天哪 -真可憐
This time…
這一次…
I bet 20 years.
我押二十年
How's that? Are you scared?
怎麼樣？害怕了？
Call.
我跟
If you lose this time, you'll only have ten years left.
如果你這次輸掉，就只剩十年壽命了
Your hand.
亮牌吧
My hand, my hand!
我的手…
Oh, my hand!
我的手！
A three bright.
一張三光
That cunning little--
這個狡猾的混蛋…
Give me back my hand!
把手還給我！
That evil bastard cheated!
那個惡棍出老千！
This was the first time. Believe me. I swear.
這是第一次，真的，我發誓
Bullshit.
胡說
Let it slide this once, okay?
這次放我一馬吧？
I can't gamble with a hand missing.
我只剩一隻手沒辦法賭博
Fine, then.
那好吧
-But all our previous games are invalid. -Yes, yes, of course.
-但是我們之前所有賭局都無效 -當然
Now you will play fair against me. Let's say I win.
現在你要和我公平賭博，假如我贏了
Then, you return my brother's life span, and all that belongs to these gods.
你要歸還我弟弟和這些神的壽命
Yes, that's right. Rightfully so.
沒錯，這樣才對
Though poor and powerless, they are still tutelary deities.
雖說他們可憐又無助 但他們依然是守護神
You've no right to take their lives.
你沒有資格奪走他們的壽命
Answer me!
回答我！
Whatever. Fine. Bring it on!
隨便了，好吧，放馬過來！
We have him now.
有他幫我們撐腰了
What is Yeon up to?
阿硯在做什麼？
He's gambling with Dokgakgwi.
和獨腳鬼賭博
Has he lost it or what?
他是不是瘋了？
I've never seen anyone beat Dokgakgwi in gambling.
我從來沒見過有人賭贏獨腳鬼
I searched everywhere, ma'am. There's no guardian stone or golden ruler.
閣長，我到處都搜遍了 沒找到守護石或金尺
He's more careful than you'd think.
他比你想像中更謹慎
-Shall I continue searching? -That's okay.
-要我繼續搜嗎？ -不必了
We'll make him give it to us himself.
我們會讓他主動交給我們的
All right.
好吧
I'm going all in.
我全押
-Is he crazy? -Playing aggressive from the start?
-他瘋了嗎？ -一開始就氣勢洶洶？
It's all or nothing now. The Dokgakgwi is terrifying when angered.
現在只能孤注一擲 獨腳鬼生氣的時候很可怕的
-Terrifying. -So, so terrifying!
-很可怕 -超級可怕！
If you call, I'll valuate yours to the price of mine.
如果你跟 我會根據我的價格評估你的壽命
One of us dies here.
我們要在這裡分個你死我活
This is too scary. I can't watch.
太可怕了，我不敢看
I fold.
我不跟
It's a high zero!
是零點！
You went all in with that awful hand?
你一手爛牌還全押？
Why didn't you call then? You would've won.
那你為什麼不跟呢？跟了就能贏
All in.
全押
Fold.
不跟
-All in. -Fold.
-全押 -不跟
-Oh, gosh! -Geez.
-天哪！ -我的天
-All in. -Fold.
-全押 -不跟
All in!
全押！
-Mountain god is such a chicken.
-山神是膽小鬼
Mountain god is scared.
山神害怕了
It's worth betting this time.
這次值得賭一把
Should I bet?
要不要賭呢？
All in.
全押
Will you call or not?
你到底跟不跟？
The problem is… is he bluffing?
問題是…他是在虛張聲勢嗎？
No, let's fold this time.
不行，這次先不跟
One last time.
最後一次
-What's wrong? -Is he dead?
-怎麼了？ -他死了嗎？
I'm warning you.
我警告你
You leave the seat, game's over.
只要你離開座位，賭局就結束
No second chances.
沒有第二次機會
Rang, hang in there a little longer. Trust me, I'll save you.
阿朗，再堅持一下 相信我，我會救你的
So much big talk for someone losing every game.
一個每局都輸的人還敢放大話
All it takes is a single round.
只要贏一局就夠了
If I lose, Rang and I will both die here.
如果我輸掉，我和阿朗都會死在這裡
Will you call or not?
你跟不跟？
-Say call, say call. -Will he be okay?
-跟吧 -他不會有事嗎？
He's the great mountain god, after all. Everyone, let's support him.
畢竟是山神，大家一起鼓勵他吧
Say call, say call!
跟吧！
-Say call! -No. Please, don't do it.
-跟吧！ -不行，拜託你不要跟
It's not a bad idea to take out a demon of that caliber in advance.
提前除掉一個厲害的妖怪也不錯
-Say call! Say call!
-跟吧！
Fine.
好
Bring it on.
放馬過來吧
Fine, I'll open my hands.
好，我要亮牌了
PAIR OF TENS
（兩張十點）
Are you sure you won't regret this?
你真的不會後悔嗎？
I'm not the regretting type.
我不是喜歡後悔的人
A PAIR OF EIGHTS
（兩張八點）
One, two, three!
一、二、三！
What's this?
這是什麼？
He lost?
他輸了嗎？
Thank you for sparing my life.
謝謝你饒我一命
Hey!
喂！
-Thank you. -Thank you, sir.
-謝謝 -謝謝大人
I'll live doing good now.
以後我會行善的
No more gambling. Don't wrestle anyone either.
不要賭博了，也不要和別人摔角
Yes, sir!
是！
-Let's go. -Okay.
-走吧 -好
-Thank you, sir.
-謝謝大人
Go on, you.
快走吧
We're grateful.
謝謝大人
-Thank you, sir. -Thank you so much.
-謝謝大人 -太感謝了
No need to thank me.
不必謝我
Just stop bothering the old hag.
不要再打擾老妖婆就好了
But why did you retrieve our life spans too?
可是你為什麼 要同時恢復我們的壽命？
It's a chaotic time for the indigenous gods.
本土神正處於一個混亂的時代
And it will continue.
而且以後也會如此
If you want to survive, find yourself a grounding.
如果你們想活下去 就要為自己找尋一席之地
Learn to live among the humans in the new world.
學會在新世界中和人類和平相處吧
-Yes, sir. -Thank you.
-是，大人 -謝謝
If the governor's office had this, something's happened to the guy I met, no?
既然總督府拿到了這個 和我接頭的人一定出事了，對吧？
He's off the grid?
他失聯了？
Not only him.
不僅是他
All our contacts based in Gyeongseong went off the grid.
所有駐紮在京城的聯絡人都失聯了
-Just how far have we been compromised? -We don't have time.
-我們的身份暴露到什麼程度了？ -沒時間了
The Governor-General's moving too.
總督也在行動
Are you saying we should proceed with this few of us?
妳是說就靠我們幾個人推進計劃嗎？
Moving with the fewest may be for the best.
以最少的人數推進計劃才好
First, I'll find out the time and place.
我先去確認時間和地點
You should all go home.
你們都回家吧
You should stay safe.
妳一定要注意安全
-Shin-ju, please protect Eun-ho. -Yes, ma'am.
-申炷，請你保護恩好 -是
I need an answer today.
今天我要問出個答案
Koo Shin-ju, what are you?
具申炷，你是什麼東西？
What do you mean by that?
什麼意思？
I was captured by the Jangsan Tiger. I met a self-proclaimed mountain god too.
我被萇山虎抓走過 還遇到一個自稱是山神的人
Don't you think it's time I knew about my comrade…
你不覺得我應該瞭解一下
who lives through gun shot wounds?
子彈都打不死的同志嗎？
You--
你…
You intend to remarry with whom?
你打算娶誰做續絃？
Ginko Tawara, my sister-in-law.
俵銀子，我的小姨子
Have you lost your mind? I don't care how many times you marry.
你瘋了嗎？我不管你要結幾次婚
But I can't let my Ginko marry a divorcee.
我不會讓我的銀子嫁給離過婚的人
-You know how I raised her! -You will change your mind
-你知道我是把她當寶貝養大的！ -等你看到這個
when you see this.
就會改變主意的
Come in.
進來
He's a member of the Manchuria-based Independence Volunteer Corps,
他是滿洲獨立志願軍的成員
responsible for the recent bombings at Gyeongseong station.
最近京城站的爆炸案就是他幹的
Are you saying that he's the one who robbed my house?
你是說他就是盜竊我家的人嗎？
That's what we thought at first.
一開始我們也是這樣認為的
But there's a catch.
但是我們另有發現
PLEASE USE THIS FOR THE INDEPENDENCE OF JOSEON
（請用它來支援朝鮮獨立運動）
Written with a typewriter.
是打字機打出來的
How many people do you think could afford to use a typewriter in Gyeongseong?
社長認為整個京城 有多少人用得起打字機？
You're trying to bring Ginko into this with this lousy note?
你們想憑區區一張字條 把銀子捲入此事嗎？
-Go ahead! -Sit back down.
-儘管試試！ -坐回去
Father-in-law.
岳父大人
We're only getting started now.
好戲才剛要開始
We have a witness.
我們有目擊者
I saw it with my own two eyes.
我親眼看到的
I saw Ms. Ginko Tawara at the station when the bombing occurred.
爆炸發生時 我在車站看到俵銀子小姐了
A fox?
狐狸？
You're a fox?
你是狐狸？
It's top secret on our side of things.
在我們這邊，這可是最高機密
That's why you said that.
難怪你會那樣說
That the world I know may not be everything.
說我瞭解的世界並非全部
You believe me?
妳相信我？
Normally, humans are disbelieving even after witnessing all.
正常情況下 人類就算親眼看到都不會相信
I want to believe you.
我想相信你
Do ghosts exist too?
這世上也有鬼嗎？
Why do you ask?
問這個幹嘛？
That's my sister.
這是我姊姊
It's the anniversary of her death soon, so I wondered if she'd come to her ritual.
她的忌日就快到了 我想知道她會不會來她的祭禮
How did she pass?
她是如何去世的？
The Chief Commissioner says it's suicide. But I don't believe that bastard.
首席專員說她是自殺 但我不相信那個混蛋
On the day she died,
她去世當天
we promised to go see the azaleas at Changgyeongwon.
我們明明約好去昌慶園看杜鵑花的
Don't tell me your sister was…
妳姊姊該不會是…
I think she was murdered by my brother-in-law.
我認為她是被我姊夫殺死的
Man, it's breezy.
風吹著好舒服
How did you win?
你是怎麼賭贏的？
Like this.
這樣
A three bright?
三光？
Don't tell me you…
你該不會是…
My hand, my hand!
我的手…
Oh, my hand!
我的手！
Though I can't gamble, I'm a quick learner.
我不會賭博沒錯，但我學得快
Wow! And you cut off his wrist for playing dirty.
哇，你砍掉他的手是為了出老千啊
It's called having double standards.
這叫雙重標準
Tell me what happened to us in the future you are from.
跟我說說我們在未來的事情吧
Want to see yourself?
你想親眼看看嗎？
All right, look at this.
好吧，看這個
It's me.
是我
I'm going to die soon.
我快要死了
If you were here, you would come to save me.
如果你還活著，一定會來救我的
But I have no one to depend on. I'm totally doomed.
但是我這次無依無靠，在劫難逃
I'm going to be reborn as a Dokdo humpback shrimp.
我要重生為一隻獨島富山蝦
So don't eat them, just in case.
所以別吃牠們了，以防萬一
I hope…
我希望…
you are reborn too.
你也重生了
But still,
但是
if we can…
如果可以…
let's meet again.
和我重逢吧
Yeon.
哥哥
Can you forgive me?
你能原諒我嗎？
You protected me, but I couldn't protect you.
你保護了我，我卻沒能保護你
Forget about me. How come you die so early?
別說我了，你為什麼死得那麼早？
-Did that human ask you to die with her? -No.
-是那個人類叫你陪她死的嗎？ -不是
It was my decision.
是我自己決定的
I've been living for infinite years neither aging nor dying.
我活了那麼多年，不會老也不會死
-This isn't so bad either. -Nothing good about it either.
-這樣也不錯 -可是也沒什麼好處
The feeling of cherishing every second of my life like a normal human.
作為普通人 我開始珍惜人生的每一秒
Living as a mortal, I finally saw the beauty filling this world.
作為凡人 我終於看到了這個世界充滿美好
By the way…
話說回來…
Did you cry?
你有哭嗎？
Did you cry a river after I died?
我死後，你是不是哭成淚人兒了？
Not really. I don't have tears to cry, you rascal.
沒有，臭小子，我沒有眼淚
Why you--
你居然…
Rang!
阿朗！
I thought you were going to die!
我以為你要死了！
-I'm not dead. -I told you! I knew it!
-我沒死 -我就說嘛！我就知道是這樣！
-You're so mean, really. -Sorry.
-你真的太壞了 -對不起
Still, I guess the last thing you wanted to see was my face?
我猜你最後想見的是我吧？
I mean-- My boss is such a hopeless romantic.
我們老大真是個無可救藥的癡情種
If I could, I would've folded him into my suitcase
如果可以，我會把他折疊起來 塞進我的行李箱
to take him to the era that I belonged to.
帶他回到我的時代
However, my little brother
但是，我的弟弟
grew up and found his own place.
長大了，也找到了自己的歸屬
Living a life of his own.
過上了他自己的生活
Who would've imagined?
誰能想得到呢？
The Japanese colonized Joseon!
日本居然殖民朝鮮了！
Wanna know what's more?
你知道還有什麼嗎？
Future Joseon will split into North and South,
未來的朝鮮會分成南北兩半
so I can't even willingly go to Baekdusan, our home!
我都不能隨心所欲地 回我們家鄉白頭山了！
I want to go home with you.
我想和你一起回家
I wonder if the persimmon tree we planted is well.
不知道我們種的柿子樹還好嗎？
So Ho-yeong, hurry and wake up.
虎影，快醒來吧
Moo-yeong.
無影
To be fully revived, I need the guardian stone and golden ruler.
如果我想完全復活 需要守護石和金尺
Okay.
知道了
I'll bring them.
我會把它們帶來的
Who is it?
是誰？
Who poisoned my well?
誰在我的井裡下毒？
It's me.
是我
Please save me!
快救救我！
Save me!
救救我！
The demons of Joseon are all a bunch of cowards.
朝鮮妖怪都是一群懦夫
They were to be captured alive.
他們是要活捉的
But I can't control my strength!
可是我控制不住力氣怎麼辦！
I'm hungry.
我餓了
Buy me a meal.
請我吃飯吧
I'm busy.
我很忙
I heard an interesting rumor.
我聽到一個有趣的傳言
What could it be?
是什麼呢？
They say there's a treasure in Myoyeongak.
據說妙緣閣裡有一件寶物
A treasure?
寶物？
-They're dead. -Lord Lee Yeon!
-他們死了 -李硯大人！
The well god, crock god, and even the totem pole disappeared.
井神、凸隆神 甚至連圖騰柱都不見了
Search the Gyeongseong grounds, and find out who's behind this.
搜索整個京城，找出兇手
Yes, sir.
是
Rang.
阿朗
-Have our guys on this. -Yes, sir!
-派我們的人追查此事 -是！
I was going to let things slide to prepare to leave,
我本來想睜隻眼閉隻眼，準備離開的
but that's not going to work.
但是不行了
I'm going to kill
我要在回家之前
all the Japanese demons before I go home.
殺死所有的日本妖怪
Four Japanese demons and two mountain gods, it's six to one.
四個日本妖怪和兩位山神對付你 等於六對一
I'll be the bait.
我來做誘餌
It's over now.
結束了
Hand over the treasure if you want to save your brother.
想救你弟弟就交出寶物吧
I'll snatch the treasure while Yeon and Moo-yeong are fighting.
我要趁阿硯和無影打架的時候 奪取寶物
I never start a losing fight.
我從來不打沒把握的仗
What if Hong-joo and Moo-yeong sides with us?
如果紅酒和無影與我們聯手呢？
Catch them with me.
和我一起抓住他們吧
As the last mountain gods of Joseon.
畢竟我們是朝鮮最後的山神
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳